his eyes very wide open for we have reason to think that some of Snowball's
secret agents are lurking among us at this moment.
>> Four days later in the late afternoon, Napoleon ordered all the animals to
assemble in the yard.
When they were all gathered together, Napoleon emerged from the farmhouse
wearing both his medals, for he had recently awarded himself Animal Hero,
First Class, and Animal Hero, Second Class.
With his nine huge dogs frisking round him and uttering growls that sent
shivers down all the animals' spines.
They all cowered silently in their places, seeming to know in advance that some
terrible thing was about to happen.
Napoleon stood sternly surveying his audience.
Then he uttered a high-pitched whimper.
Immediately the dogs bounded forward, seized four of the pigs by the ear, and
dragged them, squealing with pain and terror, to Napoleon's feet.
The pigs' ears were bleeding. The dogs had tasted blood, and for a few moments,
they appeared to go quite mad.
To the amazement of everybody, three of them flung themselves upon Boxer.
Boxer saw them coming and put out his great hoof, caught a dog in midair, and
pinned him to the ground.
The dog shrieked for mercy, and the other two fled with their tails between their legs.
Boxer looked at Napoleon to know whether he should crush the dog to death or let it go.
Napoleon appeared to change countenance, and sharply ordered Boxer to let the dog go.
Whereat Boxer lifted his hoof, and the dog slunk away, bruised and howling.
Presently the tumult died down.
The four pigs waited, trembling with guilt written on every line of their countenances.
Napoleon now called upon them to confess their crimes.
They were the same four pigs as had protested when Napoleon abolished the Sunday meetings.
Without any further prompting, they confessed that they had been secretly in
touch with Snowball ever since his expulsion, that they had collaborated with him in
destroying the windmill, and that they had entered into an agreement with him
to hand over Animal Farm to Mr.
Frederick.
They added that Snowball had privately admitted to them that he had been
Jones's secret agent for years past.
When they had finished their confession, the dogs promptly tore their throats
out, and in a terrible voice, Napoleon demanded whether any other animal had
anything to confess.
The three hens who had been the ringleaders in the attempted rebellion
over the eggs now came forward and stated that Snowball had appeared to
them in a dream and incited them to disobey Napoleon's orders.
They too were slaughtered.
Then a goose came forward and confessed to having secreted six ears of corn
during the last year's harvest and eaten them in the night.
Then a sheep confessed to having urinated in the drinking pool,
urged to do this, so she said, by Snowball.
And two other sheep confessed to having murdered an old ram, an especially
devoted follower of Napoleon, by chasing him round and round a bonfire when he
was suffering from a cough.
They were all slain on the spot.
And so the tale of confessions and executions went on until there was a
pile of corpses lying before Napoleon's feet, and the air was heavy with the
smell of blood, which had been unknown there since the expulsion of Jones.
When it was all over, the remaining animals, except for the pigs and dogs,
crept away in a body.
They were shaken and miserable.
They did not know which was more shocking, the treachery of the animals
who had leagued themselves with Snowball, or the cruel retribution they had just witnessed.
In the old days, there had often been scenes of bloodshed equally terrible,
but it seemed to all of them that it was far worse now that it was happening
among themselves.
Since Jones had left the farm until